Register to The Ernest Trow Carter Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Carter, 1879-1968; Series I; 13.75' (33 boxes)
  - Songs, I.E
    - [Song of Tahawus] The Song of Tahawas: Song for medium voice with pianoforte accompaniment / Poem by Alfred L. Donaldson; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
      On title page: G minor
    - [Song of Tahawus] The Song of Tahawas: Song for medium voice with piano-forte accompaniment / Poem by Alfred L. Donaldson; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
      On title page: A minor
    - [Song of Tahawus] The Appeal of Tahawas / Music by Ernest Carter; Poem by Alfred L. Donaldson., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
    - [Song of Tahawus] The Song of Tahawas / Poem by Alfred L. Donaldson; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([6] p.) + 1 manuscript part; 33 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
      For tenor and piano
      Inscription by Carter on title page: To Mr. George Hamlin with kindest regards
    - [Song of Tahawus] The Song of Tahawus: Song for medium voice with piano-forte accompaniment / Poem by Alfred L. Donaldson; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
      Note on title page: Published for the benefit of the Victory Mountain Park Association
    - [Song of Tahawus] The Song of Tahawus: Song for medium voice with piano-forte accompaniment / Poem by Alfred L. Donaldson; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
      Sketches for cover [?] laid in
    - [Song of Tahawus. Text] The Song of Tahawus / By Alfred L. Donaldson., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 277)
    - [Sons of Nassau] Sons of Nassau: Country first and then for Princeton: Song with piano accompaniment / Words by L. Irving Reichner; Music by Ernest Carter and L. Irving Reichner., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 278)
    - [Sons of Nassau] Sons of Nassau: "Country first and then for Princeton": Song with Piano accompaniment / Words by L. Irving Reichner; Music by Ernest Carter and L. Irving Reichner., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 278)
    - [Sons of Nassau] Sons of Nassau / Music by Ernest T. Carter '88 and L. Irving Reichner '94; Words by L. Irving Reichner '94., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 28, Folder 278)
      Two copies, one with pencil additions and note: revised accompaniment
    - [Sons of Nassau] Sons of Nassau, 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 278)
      Typescript text
    - [Songs. Selections. Text] '88 Class Songs: Princeton University., 19 p.; 15 cm. (Box 28, Folder 279)
      Includes texts to songs by Carter
    - [Spoiled Willie] Spoiled Willie / Words and Music by Ernest Carter. -- 1913 Jan. 17., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 33 cm. (Box 28, Folder 280)
      Date from bottom left corner of title page
    - [Spoiled Willie] Spoiled Willie / Words + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 33 cm. (Box 28, Folder 280)
    - [Subway air] The Subway Air / Words + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 281)
    - [Subway air] The Subway Air / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([8] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 281)
    - [Subway air] The Subway Air / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (8 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 281)
    - [Subway air. Text] The Subway Air., 4 sheets; 27 cm. (Box 28, Folder 281)
      Another incomplete copy laid in
    - [Telltales] Telltales: Song for Mezzo-Soprano with, piano-forte accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter; Words from "Youth's Companion." (Box 28, Folder 282)
      1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Telltales] Telltales / Music by Ernest Carter; Words from "Youth's Companion.", 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 36 cm. (Box 28, Folder 282)
    - [Telltales] Telltales / Music by Ernest Carter; Words from "Youth's Companion.", 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 282)
    - [Telltales] Telltales: Song for medium voice / Words from "Youth's Companion"; [music by] Ernest Carter. -- New York: G. Schirmer, c1903., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 282)
      Pl. no.: 16571
      Two copies, one with the date "Nov. 22/29" written in pencil on cover
    - [Thou lov'st me not] Thou lovest me not! / Music by Ernest Carter; a paraphrase on Heine by Mrs. Browning. -- 1890 Jun. 20., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 283)
    - [Thou lov'st me not] Thou Lov'st me not: Song with piano accompaniment / Words by Mrs. Browning; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 283)
    - [Thou lov'st me not] Thou lovest me not / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Mrs. Elizabeth B. Browning (a paraphrase of the German by Heinrich Heine), 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 283)
    - [Thou lov'st me not] Thou lov'st me not / Music by Ernest Carter; Words, a paraphrase on Heinrich Heine, by Elizabeth B. Browning. -- 1915 May 11., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 283)
      For high voice and piano
    - [Thou lov'st me not] Thou lov'st me not: Song for Medium Voice / Poem by Elizabeth B. Browning; Music by Ernest Carter. -- New York: G. Schirmer, c1902., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 283)
      Pl. no.: 16240
      Two copies, one marked by Carter
    - [Vampire] The Vampire / Words by Rudyard Kipling; Music by Ernest Carter. -- 1911 Sep. 28., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 284)
    - [Vampire] The Vampire / Words by Rudyard Kipling; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 284)
      On title page: Dedicated to and sung by David Bispham
    - [Vampire] The Vampire / Words by Rudyard Kipling; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([6] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 284)
      On title page: To Mr. David Bispham
    - [Vampire] The Vampire / Words by Rudyard Kipling; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (5 p.) + 1 manuscript part; 32 cm. (Box 28, Folder 284)
    - [Vampire] The Vampire / [words by] Rudyard Kipling; [music by] Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 284)
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = (Out of the Depths): Song for Baritone or Mezzo Soprano with piano forte accompaniment / Words by Theresa Siemerling; English (sacred) text + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([5] p.) + 1 manuscript part; 12-34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      German words
      Optional violin parts laid in
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = (Out of the Depths): Song for Baritone or Mezzo Soprano with pianoforte accompaniment / Words by Theresa Siemerling; English (sacred) text and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      German and English words
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = Despair: Song for Soprano or Tenor with accompaniment for piano forte (violin obligato ad libitum) / Words by Therese Siemerling; (English translation by the composer); Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      Sheet with text pasted to title page
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = Despair / [music by] Ernest Carter; Gedicht von Therese Siemerling., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = Despair: Lied für eine Sopran Stimme mit Klavier Begleitung / Musik von Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (4 p.) + 1 manuscript part; 12-34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      Includes violin obligato part
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = Despair: Lied für eine Singstimme mit Klavier Begleitung / von Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (4 p.) + 1 manuscript part; 31-34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Therese Siemerling., 1 manuscript part; 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      Violin obligato part
    - [Verzweiflung] Verzweiflung = Despair: Song for Medium Voice With Piano Accompaniment and Violin ad lib. / [music by] Ernest Carter; Words from "Sonne und Schatten" by Therese Siemerling. -- New York: G. Schirmer, c1908., 1 score (7 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      Includes violin ad lib. part
      Pl. no.: 20458
    - [Verzweiflung. Text] Verzweiflung = Despair / By Therese Siemerling; English translation by Ernest Carter., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 28, Folder 285)
      Two other typescript copies laid in, one includes the text to "Out of the depths"
    - [We have changed all that, you know] We have changed all that, you know / [music by] Ernest Carter; [words by] W.A., 1 manuscript score ([1] sheet); 21 cm. (Box 28, Folder 286)
    - [What the auto ought to toot] What the auto ought to toot / Ernest Carter., [1] sheet of music; 10 x 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 287)
      For unacc. voice
    - [When de co'n pone's hot] When de Co'n Pone's hot / [music by] Ernest Carter; [words by] Paul Lawrence Dunbar., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
    - [When de co'n pone's hot] When de Co'n Pone's hot / [music by] Ernest Carter; Words by Paul Lawrence Dunbar., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
    - [When de co'n pone's hot] When de Co'n Pone's Hot / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Paul Lawrence Dunbar., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
    - [When de co'n pone's hot] When de Co'n Pone's Hot: Song / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Paul Lawrence Dunbar., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
    - [When de co'n pone's hot] When de Co'n Pone's Hot / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Paul Lawrence Dunbar., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
    - [When de co'n pone's hot. Text] When de Co'n Pone's Hot / Paul Lawrence Dunbar., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
    - [When de co'n pone's hot. Text] When de co'n pone's hot / Paul Lawrence Dunbar., [1] sheet; 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 288)
      Two other typescript texts laid in
    - [When the shadows fall] When the Shadows fall: (Duet) / Words + Music by Ernest Trow Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 289)
      For mezzo-soprano, baritone, and piano
    - [When the shadows fall] When the Shadows Fall: (Duet for Mezzo-Soprano and Barytone) [sic] / Words and Music by Ernest Trow Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score ([5] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 289)
      Accompaniment for piano
    - [You've been kindly, that I know] ca. 1936., 1 manuscript score ([1] sheet); 17 x 24 cm. (Box 28, Folder 290)
      Words by Lealia Joel-Hulse
      On back: sketch for "A little farewell song"
    - [You've been kindly, that I know] 1936., [1] sheet; 8 x 13 cm. (Box 28, Folder 290)
  - Keyboard Works, I.F
    - [Ampersand march] Ampersand March: for Pianoforte / Composed by Ernest Carter. -- Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, c1890., 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 291)
      Pl. no.: 54297-3
      Two copies, one with Carter's markings, the other inscribed to his mother
    - [Ampersand march (Sketches)] Ampersand march / Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 291)
      For piano
    - [Dreams of Vienna] Dreams of Vienna: Waltzes: piano solo., 2, 4 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 29, Folder 292)
    - [Honeysuckle waltz] Honeysuckle Waltz / by Ernest Carter., [13] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 293)
      Parallel title on first p.: Geissblatt Walzer
    - [Honeysuckle Waltz] Honeysuckle Waltz = (Geissblatt Walzer) / von Ernest Carter., 13 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 293)
    - [Honeysuckle waltz] Honeysuckle Waltz / by Ernest Carter., [13] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 293)
    - [Jolly thirds] The Jolly Thirds / Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1907 Aug. 18., [5] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 294)
      Notes on first p.: 1st copy - no good; corrected Aug. 18/07
    - [Jolly thirds] Ernest Carter. -- 1907 Aug. 18., [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 294)
      Notes on first p.: First copy - no good - not written out; correct Aug. 18/07
    - [Jolly thirds] The Jolly Thirds / Ernest Carter., [4] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 294)
      Note on first p.: good copy - all others copied from this
    - [Jolly thirds] Ernest Carter., [5] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 294)
      Note on first p.: good copy
    - [Maidy and I waltzes] The "Maidy + I" Waltzes., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 295)
      Holograph in ink, title in pencil
    - [Marche fantastique à la val d'Orange] Marcia de fantastique ala de Valle de Orange / Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1879., [2] p. of music; 20 x 24 cm. (Box 29, Folder 296)
      Holograph, signed, in ink with pencil notes
      Correct title added in pencil
    - [Minute minuet] A Minute Minuet: for Pianoforte / Ernest Carter., [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 297)
      Dedication: To Polly
    - [My dainty one] My Dainty One: Gavotte: Piano., 4 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 298)
      Pencil sketch at end
    - [My dainty One] My Dainty One: Gavotte / by Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 298)
    - [My dainty one] My Dainty One: (Pizzicato) / Ernest Carter., 3 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 29, Folder 298)
      Holograph, signed
      Two photocopies laid in
    - [My dainty one] Gavotte: My Dainty One / by Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 298)
    - [Namba. Dance of the first maiden; arr.] Dance of the First Maiden: from "Namba": (dance pantomime) / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1935 Nov. 1., [2] p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 29, Folder 299)
      Note on bottom of title page: OK Nov 1/35
      On title page: Piano solo
    - [Namba. Dance of the first maiden; arr.] Dance of the First Maiden: from "Namba": (dance pantomime) / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1935 Nov. 1., [2] p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 29, Folder 299)
    - [Pastorale, strings; arr. (Sketches)] [4] p. of music; 25 x 33 cm., Holograph in pencil (Box 29, Folder 300)
      Arr. for piano
    - [Popular song without words (Sketches)] Popular Song Without Words / Ernest Carter., [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 301)
    - [Postlude in G] Postlude in G / Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 302)
      For organ
    - [Postlude in G] Postlude in G: for Organ / by Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 302)
    - [Prim frolic dance] Prim Frolic Dance: In the old style / Ernest Carter. -- c1901., 7 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 303)
      Dedication: To Dr. William Mason
    - [Prim frolic dance] Old Dance: A Prim Frolic / Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 303)
    - [Prim frolic dance] Prim Frolic Danse: (In the old style) / Ernest Carter., 6 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 303)
      manuscript in S.B. Scott's hand, in ink
    - [Prim frolic dance] Prim Frolic Dance: In the old style: for the Pianoforte / composed by Ernest Carter. -- New York: Breitkopf & Härtel, c1901., 7 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 303)
      Two copies, one inscribed by Carter to his mother
    - [Prim frolic dance] Prim Frolic Dance: (in the old style): for Pianoforte / by Ernest Carter., 4 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 303)
      Note on title page: (In the key of C major)
    - [Rague de Pussy] Rague de Pussy: (Franco-American Canned Scales): or (A Musical Joke in Scales): for Pianoforte / by Ernest Carter., 5 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 304)
      Sheet with "Interlude" laid in
    - [Rague de Pussy] Rague de Pussy / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1916 Mar. 22., 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 304)
      Date from bottom of title page
    - [Rague de Pussy] Ragtime of the Future: or Rague de Pussy: (Franco-American Canned Scales): or (A Musical Joke in Scales): for Pianoforte / by Ernest Carter., 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 304)
      Holograph, signed, in ink with pencil addition
    - [Rague de Pussy] Rague de Pussy / Ernest Carter. -- 1915 Dec., [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 304)
      Note on first p.: Spring to Fall of 1915 Finished Dec. 1915
    - [Sonaten Satz] Sonaten Satz., 5 p. of music; 25 x 32 cm. (Box 29, Folder 305)
    - [Spinning-wheel etude] Spinning-wheel Etude / Ernest Carter., [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 306)
      Note by Carter laid in
    - [Spinning-wheel etude] Spinning-wheel Etude / Ernest Carter., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 306)
    - [Trout brook] The Trout Brook: Morceau caracteristique: for Pianoforte / by Ernest Carter., 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 307)
    - [White bird. Selections; arr.] Selection of the Opera: The white Bird / Music from [sic] Ernest Carter; by Hans Avril. -- 1928 Nov. 5., 1 piano score (23 p.); 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 308)
      Arranged for piano by Hans Avril
      Date from end of score: Cologne 5. XI 28
    - [Unidentified piece, piano] Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1884-1911., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 309)
      Note: about 1884 - written out in 1911 for Daisy von Reichman; copy sent her in August 1911
    - [Unidentified piece, piano] By E.T.C. -- ca. 1883 or 1884., [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 309)
    - [Unidentified piece, piano] Ernest Carter., 5 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 309)
    - [Unidentified piece, piano] Music by Ernest Carter; after a suggestion by James Pyle. -- 1901., [1] sheet of music; 18 x 28 cm. (Box 29, Folder 309)
    - [Unidentified pieces, piano (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 29, Folder 309)
    - [Unidentified piece, piano (Sketches)] Fortsetzung der Einleitung., [1] sheet of music; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 309)
      Note: not bad: keep 10/17/50
  - Chamber and Instrumental Works, I.G
    - [Ampersand march; arr.] Ampersand March / E.T. Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.) + 5 parts; 27 x 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 310)
      For flute or piccolo, violins I-II, cornets I-II, and violoncello
      Cornet II part not included
    - [Dreams of Vienna; arr.] Waltz / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (5 p.) + 2 parts; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 311)
      Arr. for violins I-II, violoncello, and piano
      Includes violin I and violoncello parts only
    - [Fugues, string quartet, no. 1, C major] Fugue I: (for 4 Voices): (For String Quartette) / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.) + 4 parts; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 312)
    - [Fugues, string quartet, no. 2, A minor] II: Fugue: (4 Voices): For String Quartette., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.) + 4 parts; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 313)
    - [Fugues, string quartet, no. 3, B minor] III: Fantasie Fugue: (4 voices): (For String Quartette) / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.) + 4 parts; 27-34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 314)
    - [Fugues, string quartet, no. 3, B minor (Sketches)] Fugue in H moll: fur Streich Quintet mit / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 315)
    - [Gypsy dance (Sketches)] String Quartet, Gypsy Dance., [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 316)
    - [Lettargo aus der Suite "Marie"] Lettargo aus der Suite "Marie.": (Fur Streich-Quartet [sic]) / von Ernest Carter. -- 1895 May 26., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 29, Folder 317)
      Note: Op. 93 (im Schatten) Berlin 26. Mai 1895
    - [Minuet, string quartet, E minor] Minuet: for String Quartet / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 318)
    - [Namba. Dance of the first maiden; arr.] Dance of the First Maiden: from "Namba": (dance-pantomime) / by Ernest Carter., 6 manuscript parts; 32 cm. (Box 29, Folder 319)
      Arr. for clarinet in B, violins I-II, violoncello, bells and triangle, and piano
      Two sheets with unidentified musical additions laid in
      Pencil notes on title page: arranged for Piano, Violin, Clarinet, Cello (or Baritone Saxophone), Bells and Triangle; S.S. Virginia Jan. 1933 for Austin Yoder (sent him another set parts)
    - [Namba. Dance of the first maiden; arr.] Dance of the First Maiden: from "Namba": (dance pantomime) / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1934 May 22., 3 manuscript parts; 33 cm. (Box 29, Folder 319)
      Arr. for violin, violoncello (or baritone saxophone), and piano
      Date from lower left corner of first p. of piano part
      Inscription on title page: Paul Sargent, with compliments of Ernest Carter
      Sheet with unidentified musical addition laid in
    - [Namba. Dance of the first maiden; arr.] Dance of the First Maiden: from "Namba": (dance pantomime) / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1934 Sep. 7., 6 manuscript parts; 33 cm. (Box 29, Folder 319)
      Arr. for clarinet in B, violins I-II, violoncello (or baritone saxophone), bells and triangle, and piano
      Date from lower left corners of parts
    - [Namba. Dance of the first maiden; arr.] Dance of the First Maiden: from "Namba": dance-pantomime / by Ernest Carter., 3 manuscript parts; 31 cm. (Box 29, Folder 319)
      manuscript in ink on onionskin
      Arr. for violin, violoncello, and piano
      Photostats laid in
    - [Nocturne, violin, piano (Sketches)] Nocturne or Lullaby., 1 manuscript score ([1] sheet); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 320)
    - [Pastorale, oboe, strings] Pastorale: For Oboe and String Quartet / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.) + 4 parts; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 321)
    - [Pastorale, oboe, strings] Pastorale: For Oboe + String Quartet / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 321)
    - [Pastorale, strings (Sketches)] Pastorale: (Sextet for strings) / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 36 cm. (Box 29, Folder 322)
    - [Petite nocturne] Une Petite Nocturne: for Bugle in F: with left-hand piano accompaniment / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 323)
      On title page: used in Blonde Donna
    - [Prim frolic dance; arr.] A Prim Frolic: Dance in the ancient manner: For Flute, Violoncello and Harp / by Ernest Carter. -- c1901., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 324)
      Positive and negative photostats laid in
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major] String Quartet in G-Major, No. 1 / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1935., 1 manuscript score (16, 8, 7, 10 p.) + 4 parts; 34 cm. (Box 29, Folder 325-326)
      manuscript in ink in Otto Fessler's [?] hand
      Date from lower left corner of two last movements of score
      Note on old envelope: Rec'd from Ruth Watanabe, Librarian Aug. 9/51
      Positive photostat laid in
      Note on envelope containing negative photostat: complete Nov. 28/50
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major] String Quartet in G-major, No. 1 / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1908-1916., 1 manuscript score (20, 10, 7, 13 p.), bound + 4 parts: 35 cm. (Box 30, Folder 327-328)
      Dates from bottom left corners of pages of score and parts
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major. Allegro moderato] String Quartet in G: 1st Movement., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 30, Folder 329)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major. Allegro moderato] 1st Movement: Score of String Quartet in G major: Allegro Moderato / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1905-1908., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 34 cm. (Box 30, Folder 329)
      Note on bottom of title page: OK Mch. 1908
      At end: Copied by S. Coombs, 1905
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major. Allegro moderato] String Quartette / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (18 p.); 34 cm. (Box 30, Folder 329)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major. Allegro moderato] Sonaten Satz: Allegro moderato / von Ernest Carter., 4 manuscript parts; 34 cm. (Box 30, Folder 330)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major. Allegro vivace] 4th Movement: Score: Allegro: String Quartet in G Major / by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1908 Jul. 2., 1 manuscript score (13 p.); 34 cm. (Box 30, Folder 331)
      Note on bottom left corner of title page: OK July 2/08
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, G major. Allegro vivace] Fugue / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 30, Folder 331)